Nick Mariani

Morgan Hill, CA 95037 nick84742_vp7@indeedemail.com 669.327.7388

A seasoned Data Center professional ensuring the continuity of large, complex internet web hosting operations, supporting an array of critical customer infrastructure, in commercial data centers. More than 15 years direct experience in the hosting business with several major service providers, including over 25 years of combined I.T. experience.

Experienced in the area of enterprise hosting operations; which include dedicated managed, and customer colo servers, cloud computing, and network services. Each running on several different hardware and software platforms. Emphasis on service delivery to clients, quick resolution to tickets, and a broad understanding of the underlying business, and addressing the needs of clients whom I work with on a regular basis.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

General Partner / Operations

NECTARTECH, LLC January 2012 to Present

Provides I.T. private contractual support, consulting, and guidance to U.S. based cloud computing clients from remote sites from the USA and offshore locations.

Support Engineer

ZETTA, Inc - Sunnyvale, CA June 2011 to September 2011

Provide first tier support to Zetta's backup application client base on Zen/Linux/Solaris cloud computing platforms. Provide test and deployment engineering services. Support the operations function for the company.

Data Center Technical Support Specialist

SAVVIS Communications - Santa Clara, CA November 2004 to September 2010

Worked as part of a support team on assigned shifts, in a dynamic 24/7 large-scale hosting environment. Responsible for all SAVVIS Internet Data Center support escalations via tickets from main call center. Primarily responsible for providing remote-hands support within Santa Clara Data Centers around the clock, and maintain the service framework. Receive work requests by ticket, phone, or email. Work with a variety of service platforms, involving many types of different hosting setups, hardware, and customers.

Possess strong troubleshooting ability to diagnose and resolve service problems in a timely and efficient manner. Use a variety of methods to attempt to find the root cause of issues using existing

information, obtaining additional detail from the customer, deductive reasoning, and best-guess, methodical "process-of-elimination" techniques.

Perform custom builds of several production platforms for the SAVVIS Managed Hosting Service. Performed racking of hardware gear; routers, switches, servers, etc. Connect cabling to the equipment, and switching service panels. Ensure installations meet the standards for the hosting service areas. Adhere to the cabling procedures and specification for copper patch cables, as well as SM and MM fiber installations. Crimp, terminate, and test both copper and fiber cabling, as required. Perform troubleshooting of all layer 1 issues within the centers. Performed internal & customer maintenance activities involving the core network hardware in node rooms, Telco MPOE, and other areas of the data center. Made upgrades and changes to the core hosting (HR) routers, switching fabric, and associated cabling as specified by SAVVIS.

Data Center/NOC Supervisor

Exodus Communications / Cable & Wireless USA - Santa Clara, CA July 2000 to November 2004

Responsible for managing a group of 4-6 technical support staff on assigned shifts in large data centers. Performed staff scheduling, time/attendance and ensure adherence to HR policies. Perform employee evaluation benchmarking, and enforce compliance with company policy. Compiled performance and workflow metrics for senior management on a variety of items. Prepare technical staff to properly perform the support roles, deal with equipment maintenance, and complete review and documentation of their tickets and work history. Maintain and supports various topologies of hardware/software in a 24/7 mission-critical environment. Act as liaison for Exodus customers to resolve problems, coordinate service activities, and handle escalations of service issues.

Lead Network Technician/NOC Supervisor

GlobalCenter, Inc. - Frontier/Global Crossing - Sunnyvale, CA November 1999 to July 2000

Responsible for NOC (Network Operations Center) functions which monitor and maintain a world-wide IP network and commercial web servers for a leading internet infrastructure company. Act upon all risk events that involve Global Center data centers in a 24/7 customer co-location environment. Responsible for the work activities of 4-6 NOC Technicians in a 24/7 shift rotation model. Coordinated with Management on event detail that affect Global Center's customer base, including handling of outages or service issues.

Senior Data Systems Operator - EDP/Data Processing

Scientific Games, Intl - Gilroy, CA July 1990 to November 1999

7/90 - 11/99

Education

High School Diploma

Live Oak High School - Morgan Hill, CA 1987

Skills

- LAN
- IP Networking
- Linux
- Server Management
- TCP/IP
- Solaris
- Cloud Computing
- Switches
- Routers
- DNS
- Operating Systems
- Microsoft Windows
- WAN
- DHCP
- Network Support
- System Administration
- VolP
- Ethernet